<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python with R</title>
      <link>/blog/using-python-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-python-with-r/</guid>
      <description>In the class, we mostly used R for the majority of the semester so using Python was a little disconcerting. Luckily, the two languages can communicate with each other making the transition to Python much smoother with the familiar backdrop of R.
For them to talk to each other, the reticulate package is needed.
# r chunk library(reticulate) heading&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;Addition&amp;quot; one&amp;lt;-1 two&amp;lt;-2 three&amp;lt;-3 Now we can use these in a Python code chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Rashi Thakur rmt2365  0. Introduction library(tidyverse) library(ggplot2) library(dplyr) data &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;insurance.csv&amp;quot;) data &amp;lt;- na.omit(data) For this project, I chose a dataset for the amount of health insurance charges paid by individuals in the US over the period of a year. The variables are age, sex, BMI, the number of children the individual has, whether the individual is a smoker or not, region of residency (southwest, southeast, northwest, or northeast), and their insurance expenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Rashi Thakur rmt2365  Introduction For this project, I wanted to track the spread of the new coronavirus throughout the world as it is an escalating situation and, I also wanted to see its effect on the stock market as I recently learned in my finance class that the stock market is being affected by this pandemic. The first dataset chosen is about COVID-19 and the total number of infected cases and deaths in each country from the 21st of January up to the 2nd of March.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>